ACTWU Motion Picture Films 5619 F
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- 1938 ACWA Convention (Box 157)
  2) (film 5C). This film shows union officers posing for pictures outside the convention. It also shows Sidney Hillman in discussion groups. The film then cuts to a baseball game where delegates are the spectators. The end of the film shows ballots being cast in an election. Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - 1938 Convention -- 325 feet of film
- Look for the union label (Box 158)
  multiple small rolls of film, hard to determine exact amount, some on cores, some not.
- Look for the union label (Box 159)
  400 feet of film
- Local 294 -- Parade Outing (Box 160)
  [41] -- 400 feet of film
- 1936 Cleveland Convention (Box 161)
  Reel #2 [1a,b,d] - 1936; 16 mm; good, all 4 reels; Black and White; On Reel; Positive; English; 1936 ACWA Convention in Cleveland, OH; Parade; speech; Sidney Hillman; Joseph Scholssberg; Franklin Roosevelt; Canada. This film is a compilation of silent footage from the 1936 convention. The film uses subtitles provided between frames Film 1B: It shows various key union speakers telling their stories and extending their praises to the members of the ACWA including Franklin Roosevelt. The film also shows members voting on various resolutions that were brought up during the convention. 1B (12 min. long. ) 400 feet of film
- 1936 Cleveland Convention (Box 162)
  reel #3 -- [1a,b,d] - 1936; 16 mm; good, all 4 reels; Black and White; On Reel; Positive; English; 1936 ACWA Convention in Cleveland, OH; Parade; speech; Sidney Hillman; Joseph Scholssberg; Franklin Roosevelt; Canada. This film is a compilation of silent footage from the 1936 convention. The film uses subtitles provided between frames Film 1C: This reel begins with the ACWA's Canadian Delegation and their involvement in the convention, also the CIO Chairman speaks and thanks the ACWA for their help in a recent strike. Speakers here discuss the need for new legislation to be passed and a push for union political action. 1C (10 min. long) -- 400 feet of film
- 1936 Cleveland Convention (Box 163)
  reel #4 -- [1a,b,d] - 1936; 16 mm; good, all 4 reels; Black and White; On Reel; Positive; English; 1936 ACWA Convention in Cleveland, OH; Parade; speech; Sidney Hillman; Joseph Scholssberg; Franklin Roosevelt; Canada. This film is a compilation of silent footage from the 1936 convention. The film uses subtitles provided between frames Film 1D: This reel is comprised of the different union committees giving their reports on the status of the union and the goals for that year. The film also covers the Grand Ball which is held before the last day of the convention. The final session includes President Hillman and Vice President Schlossberg being reelected to their positions as well as selecting Atlantic City as the site for their next convention. 1D (11 min. long), -- 400 feet of film
- 1936 Cleveland Convention (Box 164)
- We Mourn Our Loss (Box 165)
- To Promote the General Welfare -- Truman (Box 166)
- How to bury Taft-Hartley (Box 167)
- Union Local: Films for labor (Box 168)
- So long its been good to know you (Box 169)
  [88] - Harold Mayer Production; 16 mm; good (both prints); Color; On Reel; Positive; English; ACWA, Phillips Van- Heusen Boycott; plant closing. This is a short promotional film put out by the ACWA to encourage consumers to boycott the Phillips Van-Heusen Clothing Company. The company closed numerous plants in Pennsylvania, Alabama, and Arkansas, before moving the operations to Asia. The motivation behind these closings is assumed to be labor costs associated with both union and non-union workforces in the United States. The film urges consumers not to purchase the products made by Phillips Van-Heusen. It's Been Good to Know You, 13 min. long, safety film -- 350 feet of film
- The Dream Continues (Box 170)
- Dream Continues (Box 171)
  [F14] - - moved from 5619 AV, box 10 -- 1000 feet of film
- The Case of Barbara Parsons (Box 172)
  [91] - Pt. 2 of 2 -- Morton Parker Arthur Mokier Productions; 16 mm; good; Color; On Reel; Positive; English; Grievance procedure, seniority rights and promotions, arbitration, IUE. This film tells the story of Technical Engineer, Michael Blais. Blais was passed over for a promotion he felt he should have received. Blais has performed well on the job for 19 years while an employee who has only been there 2 months was promoted (Barbara Parsons). Blais, along with his shop steward (IUE), file a grievance and proceed from there. The film follows the course of the grievance through the first 3 steps and then on to arbitration. It shows the different union and management people who handle each step and what role they play. During arbitrations, both Blais and Parsons are called to testify. The arbitrator decides in favor of the union citing that no legitimate reasoning was used when promoting Parsons and not Blais. The Case of Barbara Parsons, 52 min. long. Safety Film -- 1000 feet of film
- 1940 Selective Service; 1930's Cars in streets, trollies; 1960's Beatles // TKG: ACTWU - 06708 - Inheritance (Box 173)
  [4 rolls on cores] -- approx. 660 feet of film -- moved from 5619 F, box 11 -- one roll is only labeled #14A
- Sewing, Hand Stitching, Pressing -- ACTWU Current Members Working - roll #11 (Box 174)
  moved from 5619 F box 8 during reorganization -- approx. 350 feet of film on a core
- Interior Factory, Sewing, Pressing, Cutting/Patterns -- ACTWU Current Members Working - roll #12 (Box 175)
  moved from 5619 F box 8 during reorganization - approx. 900 feet of film on a core
- The Dream Continues - Narration -- 2/16/1986 // ACTWU: Current Members Working (Box 176)
  removed from 5619 F box 8 during reorganization - approx. 750 feet of film on a core
- ACTWU - "DREAM" - Steve York (Box 177)
  8 reels - approx. 850 feet of film on 7 cores and one film strip roll
- Testimony: Justice vs. J.P. Stevens (Box 178)
  [F13] -- approx. 1000 feet of film
- Testimony: Justice vs. J.P. Stevens (Box 179)
  approx. 1000 feet of film
- Testimony: Justice vs. J.P. Stevens (Box 180)
- Testimony: Justice vs. J.P. Stevens (Box 181)
- Testimony: Justice vs. J.P. Stevens (Box 182)
- Testimony: Justice vs. J.P. Stevens (Box 183)
- The People vs. Willie Farah (Box 184)
  approx. 900 feet of film
- 60 Minutes - J.P. Stevens (Box 185)
  moved from 5619 AV, Box 4 -- approx. 500 feet of film
- 60 Minutes - J.P. Stevens (Box 186)
  moved from 5619 AV, box 4 -- approx. 700 feet of film
- 60 Minutes - J.P. Stevens -- Broken (Box 187)
- ACTWU - L. Grey - "not used" (Box 188)
  removed from 5619 F, box 18 -- 2 cores - 400 and 200 feet of film
- Union at work (Box 189)
  reel 9 -- approx. 650 feet of film on a core
- ACTWU: Current Membership at work (Box 190)
  rolls #13 and #14 -- moved from 5619 AV, box 5 -- approx. 600 feet of film on a core
- Filmographs (Box 191)
  moved from 5619 F, box 16 -- approx. 525 feet of film on 3 cores
- Stills - Early 1900's; Knights of Labors, printing, drawing // ACTWU - roll #1A (Box 192)
  moved from 5619 F, box 16 -- approx. 300 feet of film on 2 cores
- Finley Outs (Box 193)
  reel 3 -- moved from 5619 F, box 18 -- approx. 300 feet of film on a core
- The Good Life: High Tech (Box 194)
  reel 6 -- Roll 1 and 3 -- approx. 1000 feet of film on a core
- Historical Stills // TKG: ACTWU - 06708-Inheitance - Roll #1 (Box 195)
  roll #1 -- moved from 5619 F, box 11 -- approx. 325 feet of film on a core --
- Berkshire Strike (roll 'C'); Strike, Demos (roll 'D') -- 1979 (Box 196)
  moved from 5619 F, box 16 -- approx. 375 feet of film on a core -- TKG: ACTWU -06708 - Demonstration
- Women- WWI - roll 11; WPA, NRA Strikes - roll 12 (Box 197)
  moved from 5619 F, box 13 -- approx. 400 feet of film on a core
- ACTWU - "Dream" -- 2/14/1985 (Box 198)
  approx. 550 feet of film on 2 cores and then one short filmstrip roll
- ACTWU - "Dream" (Box 199)
  R 3B -- moved from 5619 F, box 14 -- approx. 400 feet of film on a core
- ACTWU - "Dream" -- Reel 8 (Box 200)
  moved from 5619, box 14 -- approx. 450 feet of film on a core
- the Dream (Box 201)
  approx. 675 feet of film on 7 core and 2 film strips
- Amalgamated Laundry Workers (Box 202)
  Black and White stills (drawings) - 1800's; Black and White Photos - 1900-1960's - Roll #3 -- moved from 5619 F, box 11 -- approx. 610 feet of film on a core
- Asbestos - Dr. Sclikoff (Box 203)
  moved from 5619 F, box 16 -- 2 films, one on a core and one filmstrip -- approx. 800 feet of film
- Tails TKG Asbestos, Sync, Susan Vogt, EPA, Intv. Takes 2-6 (Box 204)
  moved from 5619 F, box 16 -- one film on a core -- approx. 625 feet of film
- Millwork (Black Workers) (Box 205)
  roll #7 -- ACTWU- Current Member - -moved from 5619 F, box 13 -- approx. 590 feet of film on a core
- Dialog Outs - TKG: ACTWU - 06708 - Inheritance (Box 206)
  moved from 5619 F, box 12 -- approx. 300 feet of film
- ACTWU - "Dream" (Box 207)
  moved from 5619 G, box 15 -- approx. 1000 feet of film
- ACTWU - Fiest (Box 208)
  moved from 5619 F, box 16 -- approx. 975 feet of film
- Kamber Group - 5-18-1984 -- ACTWU - 06708 - Reel #2 (Box 209)
  moved from 5619 F, box 17 -- approx. 775 feet of film
- ACTWU - Archival, Parades, Protests, Demos (Box 210)
  approx. 775 feet of film on two cores
- ACTWU - Archival, Parades, Protests, Demos (Box 211)
  approx. 700 feet of film on three cores -- one film labeled 'Original Farmer' and one is labeled 'Master Pos'
- Women's Salon (roll 151); Color opticals (roll 155); B + W opticals (roll 1162); Color opticals from WB + B (roll 161); B+W opticals from WB + B (roll 158) (Box 212)
  moved from 5619 F, box 17 -- approx. 800 feet of film on 5 cores
- Bono 'Flint'; Optically 'Flint' (roll 154); Opticals (roll 164); tails, WLHFP #1544 (roll 156); WLHP, stills - color outs (roll 149); one roll unlabeled (Box 213)
  moved from 5619 F, box 17 -- approx. 1925 feet of film in total of 6 cores
- Factories/Workers; Air Control; 1 unlabeled // ACTWU - 06708 - l. Grey - Sitdowns from "Babies and Banners" (Box 214)
  approx. 800 feet of film on 3 cores
- ACTWU - "Dream" - Pressing; Stitching Assembly (Box 215)
  Film, Tracks, CTU -- approx. 800 feet of film on 5 cores
- ACTWU - "Dream" - Sewing; Sewing Assembly (Box 216)
  Film, Tracks, CTU -- 910 feet of film on 8 film cores and 1 film strip
- Factory - Principals Shoe (Box 217)
  film #18 -- moved from 5619 F, box 16 -- approx. 250 feet of film on 1 core
- Auto Assembly Immigrants (Box 218)
  ACTWU - B/W - Reel 4 -- approx. 350 feet of film
- Film: "The Inheritance" - item #83 (Box 219)
- Film: "The Inheritance" - item #83 (Box 220)
- Film: "The Inheritance" - item #83 (Box 221)
- Film: "The Inheritance" - item #222 (Box 222)
- Film: "The Inheritance" - item #223 (Box 223)
- Film: "The Inheritance" - item #83 (Box 224)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTWU (Box 225)
- Film: Kamber Group "The Dream" (Box 226)
- Film: ACTWU (Box 227)
- Film: Kamber Group "Dream's Part I" (Box 228)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTWU R9B-10A-10B-11A-11B-11C (Box 229)
- Film: Kamber Group "The Dream" (Box 230)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTW" (Box 231)
- Film: "SMW-Pension" (Box 232)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTWU (Box 233)
- Film: WLHFP (Box 234)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTWU (Box 235)
- Film: Kamber Group "The Dream" Parts I&II (Box 236)
- Film: Kamber Group "The Dream" (Box 237)
- Film: Dialogue Reel 1 (Box 238)
- Film: "Hopewell Village" (Box 239)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTWU R-47-56 (Box 240)
- Film: Narration's Read #2 (Box 241)
- Film: SMWIA Music B (Box 242)
- Film: SMWIA Dialogue B Reel 2 (Box 243)
- Film: Premix (Box 244)
- Film: ACTWU Music B Reel 1 (Box 245)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTWU R1-6 (Box 246)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTWU R12A-12B-13A-13B-14A-14B (Box 247)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTWU Stock Pts. Pos. & Neg. (Box 248)
- Film: Kamber Group ACTWU "The Dream" R-11-17 (Box 249)
- Film: ACTWU "The Dream" (Box 250)
- Film: Kamber Group "The Dream" sound (Box 251)
- Film: WLHFP Original (Box 252)
- Film: Unlabeled (Box 253)